now excellent okay so let's go through
it coin shuffle plus plus peer-to-peer
mixing and on linkable Bitcoin
transactions this is the paper we're
talking about it's unclear the authors
are going to be able to join us if not
they'll join us next week hopefully yes
two weeks ago we talked about coin
shuffle which was the predecessor to
coin shuffle plus plus coin shuffle
dealt with the issue
removing the coordinator doing fully
decentralized coin joints but the way
that coin shuffle did it was they would
shuffle addresses by onion encrypting
them and essentially mixing the
addresses as the addresses as the
encrypted addresses passed across all
the peers as they passed across peer
they've been decrypted and then further
shuffled and we talked about why this is
a is a poor design choice because on a
scale very well and so as an example we
looked at electron cache which had only
five participants in total doing coin
joint so here's where we are in the
wasabi research Club next week will
likely do coin shuffle plus plus again
with the authors so I just wanted to
quickly run through the DC network so
the DC network was a problem posed by
Tom in 1988 and the idea is that three
cryptographers are sitting at a table
and they want to anonymously convey
whether or not they paid the bill
so one thing we notice about the dining
cryptographers protocol is that it
allows for anonymous communication among
honest peers and only honest peers will
see why in a second and it's completely
resistant to traffic analysis which is
in contrast to something like the Tor
network so one more time
three cryptographers sitting at a table
they need to communicate whether or not
they paid for
so if they didn't pay for dinner you can
think of this as a zero and if they did
you can think of this as a one and at
the end of this protocol we want to
essentially know whether someone in this
in this table paid for dinner or a dog
or not so here's how a child proposed to
do this protocol anonymously every
single user is going to look to their
right and create a hidden secret just a
simple zero or one will suffice and
we'll do this for all participants until
there are three shared secrets
each secret is only known by two
participants and what everyone is going
to do is they're going to XOR their
secrets XOR is just simply asking is the
secret on your left different from the
secret on your right if it is that's a
one if it's not that's a zero and so
every single participant XOR is their
their value as you can see here and they
speak out loud the value to the
remaining participants so you can see
here that the orange participant has a
one as a shared secret on both sides so
he's his message is zero the Green has a
one on one side and the zero so his
message is one and so forth and there's
only one additional thing we need to do
for this protocol to work which is if
you in fact are the person that wants to
convey that you paid for dinner
therefore someone made for dinner
you just XOR the value one with whatever
you have which is a fancy way of saying
whatever value you have you negate that
value you flip the bit so in this case
what we'll do
oh and so in this case if no one paid
for dinner then they'll simply say the
values they have the sum of those values
will always be even and all participants
know because the sum of the value is
even that no one at the table paid so
likely an NSA member paid but if you are
the payer in this case we'll look at
orange orange did
for the bill or just gonna flip a bit
originally orange was supposed to
declare a zero but now orange is
declaring a one and so the sum is an odd
number if the sum is odd then it means
that it was one of the individuals at
the table that was in fact the payer and
that's good and we know as well at this
that this works because if you look from
the perspective of yellow who did not
pay the bill yellow doesn't know you
know yellow does not know the secret the
shared secret between green and orange
and so yellow doesn't know whether it
was green or whether it was orange that
in fact paid the bill given the honest
given the public messages and so all
yellow knows that the sum is 3 and that
someone must have paid ok was it either
of them it's unclear to know so the
other question we had was why is it
always even why is it that you know even
if we have 800 of these people at a
dinner table and if every person only
has two shared secrets with someone on
their left and someone on their right
why is it that the XOR is always even if
we sum the XOR values across all
participants and the reason is quite
simple all participants either have a 0
or a 1 to their left unto their right if
if they have a different value than they
message 1 and if they have the same
value they message 0 and because it's in
a circle the value must always come back
to the original starting point so for
this reason if one participant goes from
a zero to a one then someone else will
have to go from a one to a zero and
that's why it's always even and this is
the same no matter what what what kind
of setup you have whether you have many
many participants or just a few so there
are two problems we have to discuss
because those are the key reasons why we
don't use these
many practical applications and it's the
key thing that's solved in coin shuffle
plus plus namely the number 1 is a
collision of messages so the only way
this protocol works is if only one
person speaks at a time or nobody speaks
so if for example let's suppose that
green actually paid for half of the bill
and orange also paid for half and so
what they're doing is they both negate
their bit when they speak out loud well
unfortunately that doesn't work what
happens there is that the the values get
negated and the entire table gets an
even sum and so unfortunately yellow who
is the only person not in the loop that
doesn't know the secret is wrong wrongly
believes that the NSA paid which is not
the case so the big thing to understand
here is that when you do a round of a DC
net you cannot have more than one person
say a message if more than one person
says a message
it actually garbles up both messages so
that's a pretty big problem so further
we have to talk about kicking disruptors
something that a malicious entity can do
in this case orange is the malicious
entity is simply not obey the protocol
so for example reveal random messages or
messages that are not X or s of what you
have or possibly even the opposite of
the XOR that you have purposefully
garbling all the other messages the
problem in this case is that if orange
does something evil like in this case
here green really did pay for the meal
or and did not pay but orange is is
saying as though he made the problem
here is that there's no way to find out
who the disrupter is in an efficient way
so in other words orange can disrupt
definitely this this protocol from from
happening and that's pretty unfortunate
so yeah so who disrupted the message
it's unclear okay
so yeah in this case yellow is just
unaware of what's going on because
yellow doesn't know whether it was green
or orange they disrupted the message so
now we're going to talk about boy Java
plus plus so in the paper
four things are discussed first the
paper discusses how peer-to-peer mixing
is is is really a natural generalization
of DC networks and this is because when
you have a peer-to-peer mixing strategy
Bitcoin we essentially have a bunch of
peers that need to anonymously post an
address for the mixing and then they
present number two is the dice mix
protocol which solves the two issues I
brought up with DC Nets namely
collisions and with malicious peers and
what's really fascinating about this
protocol is that it works in only four
plus two F rounds where F is the number
of malicious peers so given no malicious
peers on the entire protocol will and in
just four rounds and then we have gender
plus plus which applies dice mix to
Bitcoin transactions to create a
surprise I think yes one adult or
actually appear so just a quick quick
what's going on we usually just write
human yeah yeah so it we're gonna do
queenship classes again the next week
too
it's quite difficult I think two weeks
is good okay make sense
oh and don't forget to mute yourself and
your ship yes okay so okay so
tim ralphing is here which is pretty
exciting so yeah so now we're talking
about coin Channel plus plus because we
covered DC networks so dice makes
requires only four plus two F rounds and
the presence of earth militia Spears
okay so I have to come clean and say
that I did not fully understand how and
why this protocol works but essentially
the idea is that users are as opposed to
using messages that are XOR together
these DC meant messages will be power
sums and so yeah oh sorry
and so then by using yes
then excuse me then the messages are
extracted by finding the roots of the
polynomial so I laid around this myself
quite a bit and I tried to replicate
this and look at the code for hints but
I struggled quite a bit but yeah that's
where I'm at so the ideas intentional
collisions with this protocol yeah and
so the entire thing goes in four stages
firstly a Dimi Hellman key exchange
between participants then the commitment
phase where participants are committing
what their message is going to be and
then there's the DC net phase where
the participants are using power sums
over a finite field to construct their
own secure message and then there's the
confirmation phase which is the end of a
successful mix where messages are made
available and all participants have the
same anonymous messages there are the
way that dice makes handles malicious
peers is by having if ephemeral keys and
by having participants reveal their
secret key and reveal paths that allows
everyone to see who in fact is the
malicious peer to then exclude them in
the next round so that that's that's how
that's dealt with so here's an example
of these communication rounds so if you
look at the first run number one you
have the key exchange then you have the
commitment phase then then you have the
DC net and because the protocol could
not arrive at the confirmation phase
these secret keys are revealed and then
the that the pads are revealed
allowing malicious participants to be
excluded and so the protocol continues
over and over again until finally
reaches the confirmation part of of the
protocol this is probably the most
interesting thing about this protocol
which is that it scales really really
well with more participants so in the
original coin shuffle protocol there was
a sequential bit of work where users had
to shuffle decrypt and shuffle addresses
and then and then pass them to the next
peer in order and so because it was
sequential it did not scale very well
whereas this here can happen at the same
time the only thing that causes it to
scale worse as time goes on is that you
have a more complexity when it comes to
factorization of the polynomial and that
that's what's visible here in the green
so yeah so 100 peers can essentially get
through the protocol in just over 20
seconds which is pretty impressive so
yeah by using dice mix instead of the
original DC net we can achieve
guaranteed finality of the message
protocol in four plus two F rounds where
users honestly post or equal output
fresh addresses collisions and
disruptions are both effectively dealt
with protocol scales efficiently and the
others to claim that it's a substantial
improvement to coin shuffle which
required users to pass cryptic messages
sequentially so yeah that's pretty much
it I wasn't a hundred percent sure about
the some parts but hopefully we can ask
questions now okay I want to start with
meet something of a segue that it's a
exciting thing probably that Lucas when
we were talking about coin shop are not
going shuffle cross paths you figured
out how to do it with an equal amount we
do not not learned enough stock
algorithm that's not in the paper can
you elaborate on that and when team may
be able to reflect on that idea okay yes
well the main idea was that the the
paper is not such a paper and it details
how an equal output contract and such
can be can be built right so talking
with a also of that paper he said well
there is a one of my proposals that is
not in the paper is that another
protocol where you only need to know the
how much
the rest of participants want to
participate with I mean the amount so
the outputs can be split stated with his
cultural knapsack algorithm then the
participants are not a central server
who can create this unequal output
without any interaction yes so they only
need to know how much the rest of
participants are going to participate
with so my idea was in the console
protocol if if we know that we know how
much the rest are going to mix every
every participant knowing that connect
rate there the outputs right
the rest is exactly the same I mean they
can just create this onion layers of
encryption with the public keys of
repress the rest of participants to
exactly the same I mean they just
received the addresses in this case are
the output because if the address plus
the demo I mean let's connect the output
of course they don't know what they are
outputs are they just shuffle those
because otherwise in the final content
and section if they don't shuffle the
office you know the first outputs belong
to this guy this other outputs belong to
the next one so they shuffle in same way
exactly the same way so the the the last
participant the one who finally decrypt
the the the layer of encryption the last
line your encryption is only see a lot
of outputs or are unequal outputs so I
don't know if that makes sense for you
yeah I'm not sure if I got the entire
idea to be honest okay I mean I looked
after the knapsack paper once that is
really like years ago or so it would be
interesting to to know what exactly is
it's required to come up with with the
amounts here so you basically you you
simply know what you said is that you
just need to know the amount of all the
others yes
isn't that already something that like
it appears in the coins I probably don't
want to to tell each other boots right
so it's an authority just with everyone
on the plebeians
well okay yeah I mean if right if
they're going to mix the full amount on
the input yes to talking anyway okay so
but actually there's a there's a second
problem so the problem with using
amounts and general within within
something like coin shuffle and I think
here it really doesn't matter if this is
smokin choco or more crunch ahh applause
pluses actually and what I described now
is actually in the end of those paper
but it applies to normal control as well
so coin shuffle basically works by by
the idea that you use fresh addresses
for your mixing like you if you take a
new address you input it to the to the
mixing protocol and again plus plus and
in the end you can basically if
something goes wrong you can t anonymize
this round and throw away your your new
address because it I mean it has never
been used
right so it it's never been used to
receive money it will never be used in
the future so it's okay to the end of
the Masters round then then you by the
end are amazing you can figure out who's
malicious and kick them off and then you
can restart
without whiskers yes so your point is
that the amount cannot be
right right here so this is the this is
the point like the amount is something
what I call fix I think this is the term
we use in the paper also and this is
yeah there's a simple attack once you
want to use once you use fixed messages
so like that's that's for example say we
all use
let's make coin shuffle for for mixing
water fresh Bitcoin address but some
real I don't know document text file
everybody has a text file now what you
can do is you can disrupt the first
round by basically disrupting the last
message of all participants in the sense
that you us the attacker on the network
he learn you learn the output of the
protocol mean cylinder the set of all
text files it all know yet which five
belongs to who right because it's
software via anonymous that you learned
the set of all text files and what I can
in but what happens is because I disrupt
the last run by it's just simply locking
it on the last one so it basically by
blocking it on the on the network all
the other guys have to restore because
they think so
I'm offline or something and then I I
can't lock so we can assuming and the
network attacker I can block some honest
use this messages on the network so in
this so this means that the second round
also won't won't finish
because there's another guy Pierce of
the awful I know and now the the
remaining that this one still need to
restart from scratch they kick out the
day honesty editor a plot
kick them out to and now afterwards
let's say the the remaining peers that
are still on the protocol now managed to
finish the protocol and now let's say
the beginning we had five people
including me so I I went offline in the
first run then I got somebody in the
second Frances there were three three
participants left now and they have
three text files and I learned at the
beginning all the five texts for it so
the now I can just look at the two other
two that are missing and now in the in
the final output and I know one of them
is mine so I know the other one was from
the guy uploads not sure if this was
actually a Kevin next week I can and I
can bring those slides of them here will
be fantastic ensure them because anyway
I have I have slides for a lot of stuff
so this is a generic attack yet this
works whenever I can I can basically
make participants piaf loyal maybe
because I'm the network attacker locking
their messages and it's actually pretty
pretty annoying and in control because I
mean and the pepper we if you say it's
peer-to-peer but what we mean by that
it's basically peer-to-peer on the if
you look at the at the at the
transaction that's generated white
because it's in the end is basically
congruent that if you want to do this
efficient you want to run it over
server or which we hello another board
were just simply responsible for for
broadcasting messages and we don't trust
it otherwise that's the idea here but
the sunna CSV everybody connect to
London Bharat you can maybe maybe just
think of my IRC server untrusted I
receive server and what we of course
trust the server for is that it doesn't
exclude people arbitrary from the
protocol right if could say okay look
this is always sim I don't want Tim to
have anonymity is very exclude them
always and I think that's in the normal
cone shuffle that wouldn't be a big
issue because well I mean if the server
doesn't like me I can yell at it and use
another one but it's like in if you fix
messages and the attack that I mentioned
earlier comes into plate and that's
pretty annoying because like if the fire
if I send all my broadcasts why I had
the server it's very easy for the server
to block my message despite it just
summer just needs to pretend that I that
I went off Loyola yeah makes perfect
sense
for me to I mean obviously the problem
is that we have to we need to kick the
but participants all right that right
that's why it doesn't that's my idea
will not work it's also by the way if
you I'm not sure if this is on some
future agenda may be this like I guess
people also right off of when you
shuffle which was basically assuming
like assuming they have confidential
transactions where you can hide the
amounts then this is basically the
combination of hundred plus plus and
confidential transactions and there
suddenly it works with
with mixing amounts beaker steady
amounts are in commitments which which
you can recreate and which are read
randomized opposed like if if you if you
come up to the same value twice
resulting at the freaking dependent
that's why those messages as inputs to
the mixing protocol are not fixed in
that sense but okay it's just a remark
and look as long as you don't have CC
yes funny shuttle was or each in the
agenda
it was the idea was for the next week
but the next week with we will continue
with yeah look at estrogen is in the
agenda okay because I just a remark okay
all right yes like this is very very
early stuff there are also so what would
be interesting is to have something okay
let let let me start off roughly so I
think the the attack that I that I have
mentioned is so is so generic that it
applies to pretty much every anonymity
system we can think of right like even
if I sent at least FB our cave that's
maybe it's maybe too much at least every
every system where I don't trust my my
peers nitrogen so it's how it's written
in the in the paper so I was I was
thinking and I'm discouraged
I'm working on this with both of it all
again little Morgana's on chest we're
looking into relaxations of this model
where you maybe have a few trusted
sellers but in the sense that I don't
know maybe there are 20 servers and you
only need to trust one of them to be
anonymous and I and maybe it's possible
to avoid this taken in such a setting
because it's basically the attack relies
on the fact that people can stop the
protocol from from completing and it's
it's may be interesting to see if we can
get around this using some trusts maybe
I don't know know that I say it again I
think it's pretty hard for okay whatever
I think whatever I just said makes only
a little bit sense because we were
looking at other other settings I think
if you really have coin join in minds
that that won't really work because in
Cointreau and in the end I can always
refused to sign the culture transaction
with yes if you would want to use while
uShip doesn't matter because that then
you can oh yeah so like even even if I
somehow use whatever servers to avoid
that I simply come offline during the
actual mixing and and they connect
somehow continue the protocol the rest
of the people can continue the protocol
without me
I saw home find at the end zone yeah
now of course now you can say look I can
okay I can do no good stuff and it's
cool secret sharing with 20 servers so
that's probably not what I wanted hmm
okay I have another question I have but
this is the important letter people
speak yet since we are doing this next
week - what would you suggest how would
someone go and understand coin shuffle
plus plus in what what steps you would
do would you first look at the
pseudocode and then upwards and
downwards of the paper or yeah what what
what what would be a good way to
understand it because I have to admit to
you I I did not fully understand but I
really tried okay yeah let me think
about this
and I don't think look at the code I
mean the pseudocode with the paper from
a teacher but I think in that sense it's
too detailed to really understand the
protocol from that one the reason why we
very well so detailed pseudocode is that
in in coin shuffle that was rather and
in the original contra paper we it's the
description of the protocol was pretty
high level and some people try to
implement it and then screwed up so
that's why we it prefer to give the full
- even though it's it's it's oddly
beautiful in the octet of somebody
really translated from the paper without
having too much background and crypto
doesn't screw up entirely so I think I
mean I again as I said I can I can I
can't bring slides and it's try to
explain it and the way I would explain
it but I think if you if you understand
how a DC networks which I think you
looked at last week
then I worked then I would approach
conscience of loss plus simply as a way
to to set up with the zenith and then if
you look at the at the steps as we also
seen on your on your slides here
well what what do we need for this unit
we need a shed symmetric keys okay so in
the beginning it will key exchange then
we need to run the actual this is enough
and here it is strict with with the
power samus is actually not too too
essential for for an understanding of
the least not for for high level
understanding of the protocol it's
simply a way to to encode messages and
it's a it's a clever way because it
always works independently of collisions
but it doesn't give you an annuity or
anything like the entire limit is
provided by by the DC nut basically so
it's just a different encoding of things
that we sent to oh did you see that but
it doesn't happen any senses an
unlimited limit is just make sure that
we can get the message
next we can extract the messages later
without having any DC net collisions
where some people where they have got
these slots for example and some
people's and and the same slot and then
you get a extra of the messages oh and
you can get the extra message
practically thank you
and I think Adam is probably thinking
the same thing you know I would like to
see that this that I understand the
protocol with like let's say a 4-bit
message and three participants yeah that
I could do myself and I'm and I was
really struggling to do that so maybe
you can next week in the slides you can
you can you can show something of that
nature or or sort of walk through step
by step because I wasn't entirely clear
okay yeah
yeah I can try to do that perfect
I personally I I until I don't cook
something I don't understand and I kept
a first that we we were discussing so
far so I felt I have a good
understanding but but what this long I I
couldn't I was trying to go through the
pseudocode but but you have some
functions those are very cryptographic
functions done and it's not just right
you have the building blocks the sign
message very famously it's just normal
photography but then you have some some
much stranger cryptography like the
diffie-hellman key exchange which which
I'm not sure what the inputs end up to
be so yeah that's alright that's not
personal okay yeah yes it's to be honest
there is a reason why I never wrote an
implementation of this and they still
want to do but I never managed and I
think not because it's not not possible
but it's just because it's a very large
project even though it's it's already
simplified from from from the first one
shuffle so actually I mean when when we
were writing the second paper the
controller closed plus people contacted
the customer interest isn't doing a
limitation of the other one and VA even
thought them looked like I think the new
protocol is actually easier it's better
in every aspect just throw away or over
what you've written so far thoughtful
but um of course they weren't happy with
the dress take it is the reason yes the
reason why bike when Shaffer got
implemented they're like three or four
times I don't know but conscious
philosophers oh that's an interesting
question
I don't know to be honest I mean the the
story that I just mentioned okay I mean
there it was the case that like just the
new frame wasn't wasn't out yet so they
could know about it more the other
instances it pink just the last paper
didn't get so much attention there are
also there some papers that side the
first version a lot the second version
which is kind of okay if you depending
on how many how many citations you want
to F in your paper this is perfectly
appropriate but sometimes feel that
should people overlook the New World
I'm also maybe because we didn't like to
type to reverse not super clever because
it's called
it doesn't have con chopper block losses
a title read so if you if you would have
put that into the title then I guess
just show up and people cook with one
shot I don't know I'm just randomly
guessing here so it's an interesting
question another another reason why why
many people just prefer ctrl + + yes I
think this is something that only really
was really cute
when we worked on the plus plus version
is that actually kicking people so I'm
in control in the normal control it's
easy to deal with cases where people
send wrong messages and a lot of a lot
of to do work in the protocol is
figuring out who said it wrong messages
and kicked them out it's however in this
structure where you like the first peer
sends to the second one and the second
one sent to the third and so on in this
in such a structure it's much harder to
to deal with peers that appear offline
like a lot of the third guy doesn't
receive a message or claims that it
doesn't receive a message from the that
guy who's to blame but the second or the
third and how do you agree on now should
we kick out the third although the
second of all and I think for if you
have a closer look at this what you
really want on the end is again
something like a like a podcast shuttle
which we then in contrast of course plus
F anyway because we describe it like
this and then you have just the server
is untrusted IRC server in the middle
that has to find a decision over whether
some peer sent a message or not but at
least is the same decision for everybody
so we have to kind of kind of have this
broadcast functionality built in and of
course now you could go go back to Khan
shuffle and implemented you by the same
way so instead of sending the first
spear to the second set of sin and I
think the first year sent to the second
or second to third and so on it's just
everybody sends to the
in the middle yes you could do this of
course but then n' kind of new vice
communication right because liked it the
only advantage of the of the normal coin
shuffle protocol would be that it that
you don't need this this broadcast in
the sense because you only need to talk
to the next guy but yeah as I just
explained I think this is not really an
advantage interestingly I misunderstood
coin shuffle that the first time and I
implemented the broadcast protocol I
implemented between a broadcast say
nothing you know one guy talks to the
next guy I think like okay
I think assuming that you have to the
broadcast to think that in crypto wise
the first protocol this is a little bit
easier because this layout encryption
doesn't have yeah it's it's first
encryption right there's no it's just
encryption everything yes it's a layered
encryption yeah but on the other hand
another thing that we figured out when
we were looking at the second is a lot
of complexity in in coin shuffle one is
about getting the cases right in when
something goes wrong then you have a lot
of additional potential additional
message of said that Pierce need to send
and then you have a huge basically a
cases sinking on just to figure out who
is to play and
this is also something that is easier
and control plus plus I actually don't
know a fee if you roll it like that in
the paper but I think we did a general
insight there was that anyway the the
method of Terrance that you if you if
you report around which basically means
you want to be analyzed around entirely
but what you do is you reveal the secret
from your key exchange which basically
is the only secret information you have
in this round
except for your Bitcoin inside a key
okay you obviously should review that
one but like for from the mixing itself
if you haven't secret is the only secret
in the protocol this means that as soon
as everybody as soon as you review your
secret and what you sent is entirely
deterministic and this is makes it very
easy to to implement the planning
procedure that should figure out who who
misbehave because now what you can do is
I learn your secret now so and I and I
know your message looking at the
protocol so what I can do it's just
replay your entire protocol messages we
compute them and just compare them we
drive it through what you actually sign
it and if you send something else well
then you miss the earth making sure
students where appear so it's it's much
easier to implement than having this
huge case to think Lucas a Libra file
they have some things may discuss
questions they have a question because
when we have been
studying these ideas and discussed this
idea we started with con Chavo just
jumping directly to Kinshasa club class
we will review the DC Network right in
what I see is that part of the
complexity a big part of the complexity
of the octaves this protocol is about
this about the communication layer how
we communicate with others yes so why
else sorry I don't remember that paper
in details
sorry probably is everything is there
but why do you think that's the best
mechanism instead of using something
like at all for example what to simplify
the the protocol a bit you mean using do
you mean using tor as the protocol or
the Tor network has the built thing
because we are discussing how to i mean
the the difficult now for create an
encryption key a shocky right how to
broadcast how to gather I think
if that could be simplified by just
communicating with the rest of the peers
through tour for example I mean why are
we using this is a good yeah so I think
what you're saying makes makes perfect
sense and I think of you like there's
the threat of and I think there's a
reason why like the existing controlling
limitations and Adam here's Adams
implementation I think it's just be
mentioned here actually works by
leveraging tour because then suddenly
the protocol becomes much easier I mean
of course to organize crunching it's not
just it's just not just using tor you
need more like for example blind
signatures but the entire thing becomes
way simpler the reason why why we wrote
this paper is that we think it's
interesting to have a protocol where you
don't rely on tour also and mainly
because it gives you it gives you a
stronger anonymity guarantees right it's
worries towards optimize for a different
setting so another miscommunication
there's always a trade-off between yeah
between multiple efficiency and security
dimensions something like a DC DC that
is pretty slow compared to tour but it's
it's fully anonymous like observing the
network you can't you can't tell
anything where isn't were they optimized
for
or for low latency which is very
important in you if you look at websites
because you don't want to wait forever
but like but there are entire you have
to anonymity drawback thread so if you
first you trust your tour notes and of
course you don't trust them for me right
this is the CPU to trust for example
like if you if you are God note and your
ex is not work together they have the
good chance of generalizing you and the
same is true for take care that just
listens the network but came to end to
any time in correlation and and I think
the reason why tour made the straight of
this is what I said like they want low
latency because it should be usable for
for full of browsing but here actually I
think we are in a different setting and
we can actually have stroller anonymity
by something like like a decedent okay I
have another question and and again
sorry I couldn't read very deadly paper
not sure I don't remember but in this
case
I mean the message is experiencing it
right so it nobody can read that how is
this communication the communication
mechanism how is that it prevents
learning the IP addresses of the
participants oh it doesn't that's a
simple I'm sorry English please let me
let me check if I understand correctly
in going Schaffer at least given you
only communicate with the next guy so in
that case only one I'd be so only one
one participant no salon urlp right that
case is in this case is in this case the
same or although it I think this this
depends on how you implemented but let
me explain it in a different way maybe
first so I think when when we talk about
anonymity and what we actually talk
about this unlink ability should it be
able to link a pieces of data together
and the senses they belong to the same
guys and now we have running ability on
on different layers here so what what
coin shuffle is or ctrl + + is supposed
to give you is unlink ability between
your input address in the control and
your output address on the controller
now what you're asking about is unlink
ability between the input the tress on
your control and your IP address and
that's another weather and question but
it's it's a different question now
because you mentioned tor tor kind of
gives you some unlink ability between
your IP address and and whatever data
you said right so it's also in the sense
it hides your tie to IP address that's
why actually it in the in the paper we
say if you if you care about the second
form of unlink ability of not being able
to link network identifiers disappear
trusts to your messages if you care
about this through and probably you care
right because if you care about privacy
you probably care about privacy and all
layers then you should actually use tor
to to run run ties mix or to run on
contracts
which is another reason why the
implementation with the the idea of the
server and in the middle and plant
signatures is very sent over tor has an
advantage because they use tor for two
different aspects and we only need at
once
but like if you if you would run on
Pablo's plus without for which I think
was the second part of your question
then it really depends on on really how
you organize his network like if you if
you run its SSP proposal the paper model
with the server in the middle that's
only trusted for pro basically doing the
broadcast right and you don't trust it
for anonymity or one for let's really
say in the following abilities between
inputs and outputs of the mixing then
it's it's just the case that everybody
connects to the server right so the only
guy that learns your IP addresses in the
end is the server of course you don't
want to trust it but it leave this it's
it's better than then sharing your
Pinterest with everybody right so I
think like the basic the basic guarantee
of coin-shop applause pluses also is
always there also if you run it without
without or if you additionally I want to
hide IP addresses then it's good idea to
run it over to or also mother since we
are on this topic new healthy twenty
second benchmark there in the paper
so how would it change the store that's
a good question hey I don't know I mean
it certainly it's lower of course but
that's in question I hope it's not too
much today
I mean to
figure out the things we need to knead
it with me to test it I mean my office
that it wouldn't be terrible because I
think Ben would wise towards mostly of
cash nowadays and one of the advantages
of the protocol instead it has a
constant number of rounds so like
latency wise yeah it's it's not so fun
to have silane loops of a low latency
because you only four rounds and I think
that the most annoying thing about tor
would be that like in the experiment at
the paper we assumed that like everybody
connects to this little dot this podcast
server in the middle and they all have
the same bandwidth to the to the middle
node which is the optimal setting and
because the protocol is synchronized so
for every round you need to wait for the
last method from everybody and basically
the portal that is the slowest here and
then if you imagine like 50 peers
connecting wires Worf
then they probably have just already but
either not only because their internet
connection is as different manhoods just
by random selection of for tor routers
they will have different levels and then
we have to to wait for the slowest one
on every of the four runs I can actually
tell exactly how much is this it is the
west here is going to be because in
wasabi we the same issue and we some
round runs were failing and we were not
suspecting dosa and then we started
logging that the peers
flying with the message too late and it
turns out we had to elevate the timer to
two minutes I still have no idea why it
had to be that large why they aren't
flying so late but some the slowest
fears are colliding two minutes
so it's it's not very encouraging no yes
if they're not chosen to lead I don't
think this is fish well you don't matter
because another thing that we realized
it's van and they have to query the word
transaction which is I don't know a
kilobyte or yeah maybe a Philip I'd the
they are applying slower then when they
have to query the just just just some
small random data which which is
interesting because it should not be the
case because the issue with tourists
around the communication rounds and not
the amount of data so so there is that
maybe it's one minute mmm I don't think
half a minute
but yeah sorry just the I suspect that
the problem is we are using in a new
serie a new ship which means a new
negotiation and all a lot of
cryptography and handshake with the
entry point
finding hiding service directory to make
that it is like a DNS for hydrant
services right all that negotiation
sometimes read it fast and sometimes
really slow because you in fact it
first aquaria directory authority or
consulate that says it's really happy
the the creation of a new CEO click one
of the secret is is is that where the
communication is is is quite easy the
the performance i need the device
actually we are using new streams that's
a little bit different and those things
are already theater and actually because
i drug tests for it when a stream is not
be a tough yet then death then what is
going to just put it in an already you
stream so it doesn't want to be in our
performance anyway if we are we are we
are going out of the token careful do
you have something not really just think
about all the stuff you be sorry about
oh yes yeah if one of the rounds fails
all of the participants have to reveal
their messages correct right so I'm just
thinking practically speaking it would
mean that if we're working with like
like a wallet and and it reveals its
addresses those addresses can never be
used again right there
I think that that's the that's one of
the fundamental dears that you basically
you you really use a dress that you
never basically used before and then if
you if you know you throw the way you
will also never use it in the future
okay
that's pretty clear so are you familiar
I mean this might be very rude but are
you well familiar with it with zero link
and what how wasabi is working I'm not
sure I know a little bit maybe maybe
maybe just explaining what you want to
say and from your research if you think
that what sabe would be more secure
safer or look better if it was using a
coin shuffle plus plus model because
right now what sabe uses you know a
server that that does a blind signing of
secret outlets right yes I think
ignoring all other trade offs I think
such a model would be would be
preferable really because it writes a
stronger form of anonymity and it
doesn't rely on on tour so that but as I
said there are there are trade offs and
it's I taste a lot that it's possible to
implement control plus plus in the
meaningful way and assumingly you have
such an implementation and assuming I
somehow some quadrant future really need
to look because some of the to it
the question is really like how old its
perform in practice because former arms
of course is the it's the optimal case
and it's kind of nice but if you have us
dropping out for whatever reason you add
rounds and you have to restart and now
if Adam is telling me ok like even even
with it wasabi or the zero dinky we
already have like time odds of two
minutes
yeah it's larger than I expected to be
honest but I think it's it's something
that that really you should look into
because I said I think like from our
from a privacy point of view it's
actually the stronger model also not
relying on to working see the advantage
that some people may not be able to use
to offer for various reasons and here
they they still get a meaningful
anonymity currency whereas if you really
rely on to you know you know you can run
away
no you cannot which was my office
working fiddle okay yeah I don't know
what what you mean I can't tell for sure
what he was referring to but when cash
shop who came out I had I had to look at
the implementation and I found multiple
pretty severe floss of course then it
was github projects in the early days
and what we'll used I think they they
fix these floors at least they they they
told me and actually I will pop up them
one on github
yeah as far as I know now people have
looked at the at the at the
implementation and it seems better but I
have never looked at the decree Anna
I mean indicating because they're the
flaws were so heavy I actually want
people wrote this one on on Twitter and
total eclipses problem and then revenues
people yelled at me for for doing this
so what I heard is that they that they
really approved for the evening
seriously I've never looked did he
cancel
I don't know actively improved just to
be sure they implemented queenship not
quite requests that's right if they
implemented coin shuffle
this was another this was one of the
mentioned instances where it also it
also looks a little little bit
suspicious right because I think I mean
a it was you maybe it's a little bit
harder the prices plus plus version but
I think if you if you before you start
such a project at least that's the way I
would do it I would first do a lot of
research on the background and try like
look at various trade-offs and and and
different approaches and I think like if
you if you do that work you you should
find closure for plus plus and I think
this was also we might look to me a
little bit like okay they didn't really
spend time freaking aprox
I mean I can give you an alternative
violence ability I guarantee I got the
basic idea right away I can just work
out everything from there by myself even
if I don't win theory of the paper very
carefully with Queen shuffle plus cos I
was reading it very carefully but I
still don't get the essence I guess also
party our responsibility because like if
you let the paper go right but you have
previews later freezes which guarantees
some some properties of the diziness
that in the original edition of protocol
it's not guaranteed is that it would be
to think about it I think that's a good
way to think about yeah maybe maybe one
thing I can add here but no like of
course there's not a danger that this
email confuses you more I hope not
there is actually a variation and I can
put the link here okay and putting the
link here but but really thoughts and
then I don't want to say don't look at
it but this is really like not explained
in a
in an improper way so please please
don't look at it if you want to
understand control or anything but
actually because like the the protocol
is pretty pretty involved I also work on
on a simpler version of it which
basically raises it to 4 plus 3 F France
but it's conceptually simpler and closer
to original DC note and that this is
totally not not ready and pseudocode
there's there's basically there's just a
little bit of text and the long
pseudocode I think the pseudocode is not
even consistent in services we need work
and progress and ask if you look at it
though - don't try to understand that
because like I think you won't
understand that just because it's broke
from the way it's written there but you
just want to find out that yeah
like even even when I wanted to when I
thought about implementing this I
wondered how this can be simplified
because it's awfully complex or
something that's great thank you and so
when I think like earlier I mentioned
that I am looking into some some other
models that were recently and I think
one of the things he also wanted to is
drive this a little bit further to get
this blur protocol which also to be the
computation you look at first at the
expense of adding so when you clarify
the link you sent us I actually happen
to have read this
it didn't help that much understanding I
think that yeah that's what I'm saying
like you think it doesn't have it all
it's it's more like my personal notes
than anything ready to be understood
alright thank you
like if y'all would look at the paper
and no one really understands it maybe
we also have to make it accessible to
people
my idea is that I'm going to just jump
right to the pseudocode and try to code
it
well jump right to the building books
try to call the building blocks and then
back to and then to the sizzle code when
I hope for the best
I think one of the annoying things that
always sp8
this is that I think like when I when I
take time to look at this again but what
always bothers me is really that you
also need some some some abroad cost
layer to do this and I already said this
on my mind when I was trying to learn
that but but I guess I should just
forget about this for a moment and
really write the right to the crypto
part of it and for forget about not
working and then I mean because it's
really like a layered thing with it's a
different layer with that do you think a
simple peer-to-peer network that's using
just the flawed idea from the beginning
like big message I think that this
so much because it's I guess through so
slowly if you think like this is
something similar to to to see your name
comes really close right like something
where people can connect Wyeth war I
mean they wouldn't have to but I can and
it's a kind of central point that helps
helps organizing and also he I think he
has the same problem right you need to
try and Pierce to mix it in the first
place right I think that's a did some of
the other half problems that sig Norton
and although the mixing process
[Music]
the sorry I was just speaking a note for
my stuff so I don't you guys have
anything but regarding each section so
okay you said you can not say yes
it's recorded here you use this morning
me it's recorded hello
yes I can hear you
we can hear you Alan
okay it seems Adam he's got sorry I'm
here for some reason I couldn't hear
anything did you repeat that so yeah if
there are no further questions I think
we should probably let him get back to
his work so are there any other
questions yes so because we said in the
beginning that it's not going to be
recorded it's going to be just a warm-up
does anyone has any objections from
publishing this I think it's going
Matthew do I think we wish about policy
no no even when it's published and I
really have a public commitment that the
PT annex right I don't know do you guys
have any topics now I just have a
comment because you know a decentralized
protocol for conjoining Midcoast it's
great and if you don't need to use store
it's even better right
the problem is that we if we use some
kind of bulletin board a centralized one
then probably we need to use store de
veau to keep that server so it's it's a
PDA anything the decentralized the
peer-to-peer communication is is
required otherwise all the benefits I
think go away
and the advantages that people wouldn't
have to close their tour circuit they
could keep their tour circuit open up
for the entire round yeah I think they
are something right like yes so I agree
I would love to have a protocol that's
fully decentralized I think no one
figured that out so far yeah at least
eighty advantage should be that SSA like
you don't need to rely on a multiple
four circuits but if you bring in the
end you really want to connect or to the
center so to use taught to connect to
the central power and then you can
really ask the question like okay is it
worth all the hassle oh there is one
more thing you remember of the coin join
me do you remember the Queen Cheney tuft
yeah sure other point because I didn't
say one of the problem each page one
point or or it's quite a general problem
that how do you how do you establish
connection between 140 and another
without breaking that existing user
workflow
there might be a way at least you know
Wichita fruits which the fruit the
public is going to be exposed in that in
the address oh yeah okay you mean you
can see some from Flickr uh-huh so now
what we can do is that when you give me
your Bitcoin address to pay you money
then I can encrypt a message to your
public key and I'm broadcast it to the
network you were me you are listening to
do that message and the new technique
that message only you can decrypt it and
then that message actually contains my
mature endpoint and we actually have a
peer-to-peer communication between the
two of us and the user doesn't even know
that it's not a normal between
transaction and then you can do p2
endpoint major avoidance even a likely
transaction in the background so I think
that's that's that's exciting
anyway oh that's great and in fact I'm
opposed to pay or something like that
could be possible too I mean the two
parties can join for painting yes yes
hey maybe I think one of the hard things
is really like establishing in the show
connections and then I think if I can
figure that out clearly then can do a
lot of stuff yeah exactly and you don't
even have to as far as I understand the
cryptography can be reused for any other
purpose because you are just thankfully
them a message that can be decrypted
whoever owns the public whoever owns the
private key so who based on that message
that you ain't lived it's a question you
cannot figure out which bit why not just
you are encrypting a message is that
correct
so there are 1000 encryption schemes
where you just from the encrypted
message you don't see for which of the
key it's encrypted yeah
is that what's being useful yeah I mean
temporal doesn't use encryption with but
like the public keys are elliptic curve
keys and there are elliptic curve and
coupon schemes where you can so for
which public key cipher text so so that
exists I think you certainly to do
something because now well it depends
depends on how many messages you get it
right because if you if you can't easily
tell from the message that it didn't for
you you need to you need to try to need
to try to the craft every message just
to figure out if it's good for you and
this can be exactly but it's not a
problem because you know when is the
message coming so at that point of time
you start listening to the yes me right
it's actually easier and as for example
and whenever they have a similar model
right for you basically you have to look
at every every transaction on the
blockchain and try to receive it and
because you don't know if it's a
transaction for you know but here you
use a little bit different right because
it only to you only need to listen at
that point to this idea
yeah Phineas later know what's
interesting in your Queen shuffle paper
or if you support classes I don't know
in one of the paper I think the question
for the 2014 even that was talking about
wait